Emmanuel Onwubuya

(+49) 157 39814757 Hannover, Germany emyraeleson@gmail.com

Junior Data Analyst

GitHub: Emyrael LinkedIn: Emmanuel-Onwubuya

Detailed Data Analyst Graduate Student well-versed in various data analysis, data science and machine learning methods. Independent and versatile individual skillful in identifying data issues and monitoring existing metrics. Offering 2 years of experience collecting data, establishing facts and drawing valid conclusions. Proficient in python and various analytic tools paired with first-rate report and writing abilities.

SKILLS

Tech Stack Python, SQL Git, LTFX, ,Hadoop, Spark, Tableau, PowerBI, MS-Excel, Google-sheets, AWS. **Personal Skills** Clear Report Writing, Creative thinking, Critical thinking, Teamwork and Collaboration.

Languages English(Native Speaker), German (Basic level), Russian (Intermediate).

WORK EXPERIENCE

Working Student Data Analytics

10-2021 - 02-2022

Domicil Real Estate Group

Munich, Germany

- Investigated, corrected and escalated real estate models and project problems.
- Managed implementation of Real Estate sales and acquisition models to meet company needs and flexibility which increased
- · Utilized various professional statistical and data processing techniques to maintain large databases used for storage and querying of data.
- Tech stacks been used were SQL and MS-Excel.

Intern Data Analyst

03-2021 - -09-2021

London, United Kingdom

Gleensite

- Collected real estate datasets globally and applied data wrangling techniques to clean and unify complex data sets for easy access and analysis.
- Applied predictive models using machine learning algorithms, improving accuracy and reliability of models to about 85% by finding correlations between all datasets and feautures.
- Identified, analyzed and interpreted trends or patterns in complex data sets by finding correlations and visualizing with charts.
- Tech stacks been used were Tableau, python and helper modules such as matplotlib,pytorch,sklearn,numpy and pandas.

Intern Data and Marketing Analytics

02-2019 - 08-2019

TopKonsult

Moscow, Russia

- Imported, inspected, cleaned, transformed and interpreted collections of data from various stakeholders to assist data experts in developing marketing mix models that increased revenue of these businesses.
- Worked closely with team of Senior BI analysts to improve the customer retention and KPI metrics of stakeholders businesses by about 83%.
- Created and maintained data visualizations and useful insights that educated, informed and engaged business partners on key metrics and performance measures on a weekly, monthly and quarterly basis.
- Tech stacks been used were SQL, Power BI, MS-Excel.

EDUCATION

Master in Data Analytics, Universität Hildesheim

2020-Present

Relevant Courses: Big Data Analytics, Machine Learning, Distributed Data Analytics.

Current Grade: 2.3

Bachelor of Engineering Technology: Information Systems And Technologies,

Voronezh State University Engineering Technologies - Russia

2016 - 2020

High School Leaving Certificate, School For The Gifted - Nigeria

2010 - 2013

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Implemented and designed a machine learning system for big medical data that predicted risks of diabetes diagnosis for several age groups which achieved more than 80% accuracy during my bachelor thesis.
- Applied machine learning predictive models and techniques to real estate datasets using python programming language during my time at Gleensite which helped in discovering important features and patterns that facilitated real estate acquisition and also generated more revenue for the company.